{
    "question": "buat kalimat pujian + responnya tentang memuji keindahan alam, memuji mother, father, granpa/ma, teacher, brother and sister, friend, best friend pet, your self",
    "attachments": [],
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "Me : Mom, you are so beautiful in this night.\nMom : really? You never told me before mommy use beauty fash.\nMe : yes mom, you are A princess for daddy tonight, let tell Daddy, if Daddy shock, ask A opinion about you mom.\nMom : Ok , thankyou my sweetheart, i love you.",
            "attachments": []
        }
    ],
    "related_questions": [
        {
            "slug": "contoh-percakapan-expression-care-826",
            "question": "Contoh percakapan expression care",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "how poor you are<br>what a pity<br>i am sorry to hear that",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "Situation : Your friend is sad.<br><br>Ana : <strong>Are you okay? You look so sad.</strong><br>Nia : <em>No, I&#039;m not okay.</em> I feel so sad because I had a fight with my brother yesterday.<br>Ana : Why?<br>Nia : He took my favorite novel without asking my permission and he ripped it! How can I not sad? He even not sorry at all and when I yelled at him, he yelled me back with his ridiculous reason that why should I got sad over a novel!<br>Ana : You must be really hurt...<br>Nia : Of couse I do.<br>Ana : <strong>What should I do to cheer you up?</strong><br>Nia : <em>Thanks for your attention</em> but no, sorry.<br>Ana : <strong>Really?</strong> I&#039;m sorry I can&#039;t help you much.<br>Nia: <em>Yeah, thanks</em>.<br><br><strong>bold: expressions<br></strong><em>italic: responses</em><strong><br></strong>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "jelasin-tentang-present-perfect-tense-920",
            "question": "Jelasin tentang present perfect tense\u00a0",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Present perfect adalah tenses yang menyatakan bahwa kejadian sudah dilakukan.<br>Rumus : S + Have/Has(Auxiliary) + V3<br>Misal : I have done my homework<br>Unsur : I = Subject<br>Have = Aux/Have/Has<br>Done = V3<br>Homework = Object<br>Umumnya ditambahkan kata Since + Time<br>Jadi : I have done my homework since this morning<br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "present perfect itu berhubungan dengan kejadian yang sudah selesai. kata kuncinya sih ada kata \"sudah\", \"baru saja\", dsb.<br><br>misalkan \"saya sudah mengerjakan PR\", atau i have done my homework<br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "their-motivationimprove-if-they-858",
            "question": "Their motivation...............(improve) if they..........................(kick) a goal during the first half",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "their motivation increases when the kick goal during the first half<br><br>kalau salah gak apa-apa ya<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "apa-bedanya-conditional-type-1-2-dan-3-320",
            "question": "Apa bedanya conditional type 1, 2 dan 3 ???",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "if conditional sentences? beda tenses-nya, sama fact-nya",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "Type 1 = Real / Present Conditional (terjadi sekarang)<br>Form = If + S + V1..., I + will + V1...<br>Example = If I have money, I will treat you<br>Meaning = it may/ may not happen. Jadi artinya bisa terjadi atau tidak.<br><br>Type 2 = Contrary to the present fact (bertentangan sama yang terjadi pada kenyataan)<br>Form = If + S + V2..., I + would + V1...<br>Example = <br>a. If I <u>had money,</u> I would treat you<br>b. If I <u>were</u> you, I would leave him<br>Meaning = <br>a1. I don&#039;t <u>have money</u>, so I dont treat you, or<br>a2. I don&#039;t treat you, because I don&#039;t have money<br>b. I<u>&#039;m</u> not you, so I don&#039;t leave him<br>(intinya kalau conditional 2, penyataan dalam v2, arti dalam v1)<br><br>Type 3 <br>Form = If + S + had + V3..., I + would + have + V3...<br>Example = <br>a. If I had had money, I would have treated you<br>b. If my father had got marred again, my mother would have killed him<br>Meaning = <br>a. I didn&#039;t have money, so I didn&#039;t treat you<br>b. My father didn&#039;t get married again, so my mother didn&#039;t kill him<br>(intinya kalau conditional 3, penyataan dalam v3, arti dalam v2)<br><br><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "ubahlah-menjadi-indirect-speech-1-kiki-said-whats-will-you-962",
            "question": "Ubahlah menjadi indirect speech!    1. Kiki said '' What's will you buy in the mall?''\r\n2. Mrs. Maria said '' Can you speak englsh well?''\r\n3. Yuda said Tika '' Are you from Surabaya?''",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "kalau kalimatnya pertanyaan sebaiknya jangan pakai &#039;said&#039; tapi pakai &#039;asked (verb 2 dari ask)&#039;, jadinya...<br>1. Kiki asked me what would I buy in the mall : menggunakan me karena menceritakan kembali<br>2. Mrs. Maria asked me if I could speak English very well\u00a0: menggunakan me karena menceritakan kembali<br>3. Yuda asked Tika if\u00a0was she from Surabaya\u00a0: menggunakan she karena menceritakan kembali<br><br>semoga membantu :)",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "1. kiki asked me what would i buy in the mall.<br>2. Mrs. Maria asked me can i speak English well<br>3. Yuda asked Tika was she from Surabaya<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "contoh-percakapan-expressions-of-surprise-untuk-dua-orang-622",
            "question": "Contoh percakapan \"Expressions of surprise\" Untuk dua orang?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Dina : Hi dani did you know that everyone in this school is talking about you because\u00a0you are the winner of the sains olympiad?<br>Dani : Wow, what a surprise i can&#039;t believe it<br>Dina : Yeah you are the winner good job my friend<br>Dani : Thanks a lot dina<br>Dina : You&#039;re welcome dani",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "bantu-nyusun-kata-kata-ne-jadi-klimat-yg-bner-ya-yang-dimulai-dri-452",
            "question": "Bantu nyusun kata-kata ne jadi klimat yg bner ya yang dimulai dri yg bergaris bawah sama bantu buatkan CONDITIONAL SENTENCE TIPE 2    arrange the jumbled words to form meaningful sentences,starting with the underlined words.\r\n1. phone-puppet-his-invite-the-I-number-my-see-Finto-know-will-if-show-to-I-at-place\r\n2. and-holiday-Bali-if-have-will-his-Lombok-long-go-year-Mr. Kukuh-family-to-they-and-this-a\u00a0mohon di bantu",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "1. If\u00a0 I know his phone number, I will invite Finto to the puppet show at my place.<br>2. If Mr. Kukuh and his family go to Bali, they will have a long holiday to Lombok this year.<br>Sorry kalau salah, baru pemula hehehe<br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "terjemahan-teks-the-spying-parrot-892",
            "question": "Terjemahan teks the spying parrot",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Ini terjemahannnya<br>Mata-Mata burung beo <br>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "mata-mata burung beo",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "sebutkan-kata-sifat-dari-pengelompokan-tersebut-sebanyak-banyak-851",
            "question": "Sebutkan kata sifat dari pengelompokan tersebut! (sebanyak-banyaknya)    menurut:1.Skin (Cool, Ho, ...)\r\n\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 2. Place (in,at,on,\u00a0...)\r\n\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 3. Age (New,old,\u00a0...)\r\n\u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 \u00a0 4. Nose (sweet, smelling, ...)\r\n\r\nTolong kerjasamanya Friend's.. thanks so'much!",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "Skin = cool, hot, soft, dirty, clean, rude, ugly, beautiful\nPlace : in, on, at, beside, behind, in front, between.\nAge : old, young, new,",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "buatin-sinopsis-film-cloudy-a-chance-of-meatballs-2-dong-pake-bhs-151",
            "question": "buatin sinopsis film cloudy a chance of meatballs 2 dong pake bhs indonesia gpp..nanti aku yang translate sendiri...tolong bantu ya",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "It&#039;s always been Flint&#039;s dream \nto be recognized as a great inventor, but everything changes when he \ndiscovers that his most infamous machine (which turns water into food) \nis still operating and is now creating food-animal hybrids - \n\"foodimals!\" With the fate of humanity in his hands, Chester sends Flint\n and his friends on a dangerously delicious mission - to battle hungry \ntacodiles, shrimpanzees, hippotatomuses, cheespiders and other food \ncreatures to save the world again!            \n                <span>- <span>Written by\nColumbia Pictures</span></span>        \n            <span>\nFlint Lockwood is a genius who created a machine that turns water into \nfood which went out of control. Flint would stop it. He would set out to\n build his own lab with Sam Sparks. But Chester V, the scientist who \ninspired Flint comes to the island to clean up the mess, the machine \nmade, and offers Flint a job at his lab. Flint takes it. Later, Dr. V \ntells him that the machine is now creating living food\n and they could be a threat. So he goes back to the island along with \nhis friends including Sam to stop it. But Sam tells flint that they \ncould acting hastily but Dr. V convinces Flint otherwise. So they leave \nFlint and eventually learn the truth.            </span><br>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}